<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gadget | My Thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://mattdurham.github.io/blog/categories/gadget/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mattdurham.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-09T22:23:45-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://mattdurham.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matt Durham]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smart Alec Bag]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattdurham.github.io/blog/2013/02/06/Tom+Bihn+-+Smart+Alec+Bag/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattdurham.github.io/blog/2013/02/06/Tom Bihn - Smart Alec Bag</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.tombihn.com/PROD/TB0103.html">Tom Bihn Smart Alec</a> is my current bag of choice. Before that I went with a <a href="http://www.saddlebackleather.com/Classic-Briefcase?sc=8&amp;category=301406">Saddleback Leather</a> bag that I loved. The Saddleback had so much character, it felts indesctructible but alas it weighed somewhere around 1000 pounds. I finally decided to look for something different, I quickly went to an <a href="http://www.stmbags.com/catalog/macbook-bag-13-inch/scout2-small-laptop-shoulder-bag/">STM Scout</a> has a in betweener bag for my air. It worked and I still have it for some purposes but it didn&rsquo;t feel how I wanted it. So I started the search and found rave reviews of Tom Bihn items. So I took the plunge and ordered the Smart Alec along with a brain cell, plus a few odds and ends.</p>

<p>Let me tell you what I carry in my bag</p>

<ul>
<li>15" Macbook Retina Pro (Horrible name)</li>
<li>320GB Western Digital USB 3.0 Drive</li>
<li>Charger with plugbug attachment</li>
<li>Micro USB</li>
<li>Lightening Cable</li>
<li>Apple 30 pin connector</li>
<li>2-3 Notebooks</li>
<li>Collection of G2 pens</li>
<li>Kindle e-ink reader</li>
</ul>


<p>Everything fits easily and if I travel I add my iPad, some other connectors and assorted other handy bits. So that if all I have is my backpack I can manage. Everything is easy to get to, I like the fact it does not have 200 spots to put things. Instead it has 6 major parts, two large pockets on each side. On the top is a pair of zippered pockets. The brain cell for the laptop. Finally the main pocket for all the odds and ends. After several months I found a place for everything and now its pretty straight forward.</p>

<p>The zippers are extremely easy to slide, everything feels secure and high quality. I have no major downsides to this bag, its simple well built and effective. It is a bit pricey but then again it protects a 2200 computer.</p>

<p>Final thought. The logo is pretty awesome!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
